Guide to the Collection of Bookplates by Edwin Davis French
Yale University Arts Library
Collection of bookplates by Edwin Davis French
1893-1915
BKP 49
Yale University Arts Library
3.34
(8 boxes)
This collection contains bookplates, original artwork, trial proofs, artist's proofs, additional process materials, and correspondence related to the production and/or exchange of bookplates by Edwin Davis French.
French, Edwin Davis, 1851-1906
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Yale Bookplate Collection was formerly housed in Sterling Memorial Library. The collection was incorporated into the Arts of the Book Collection in 1984 and then moved to the Seeley G. Mudd Library in 1990. In 2011, it was transferred to the Robert B. Haas Family Arts Library.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Edwin Davis French (1851-1906) was a designer and engraver born in North Attleboro, MA. In 1876 he moved to New York, NY, and he worked as a silver engraver and designer for Frank M. Whiting & Company until 1894. He also studied at the Art Students League. French became focused on copper engraving and designed his first bookplate in 1893. In 1897 he moved to Saranac Lake, NY, and he produced over 300 bookplate designs between 1893 and his death in 1906.
Reference: Brainerd, Ira Hutchinson. Edwin Davis French: A Memorial; His Life, His Art. New York: privately printed [De Vinne Press], 1908.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains bookplates, original artwork, trial proofs, artist's proofs, additional process materials, and correspondence related to the production and/or exchange of bookplates by Edwin Davis French.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by patron.
Bookplates, American; Bookplates -- Specimens.; Bookplates; Artists' proofs; French, Edwin Davis, 1851-1906
- Box Listing
  - Adams, Edward Dean, 1902; 8 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes two signed prints.
  - Adams, Ernest Kempton, 1902; 10 items (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Includes original sketch; three signed prints.
  - Adams, Frances Amelia, 1901; 8 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Includes two signed prints; letter from [Frances] A. Adams to Mr. Merrill.
  - Adams, Ruth, 1900; 7 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Includes two signed prints; letter to Miss Allene from Ruth Adams dated May 2, 1903.
  - Adams, Walter B., 1902; 7 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Includes three signed prints.
  - Adriance Memorial Library, 1902; 4 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Includes one signed print.
  - Alexander, Amy B., 1900; 6 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    One signed print.
  - Alexander, Charles B., 1895; 4 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Includes newspaper article describing indictment of C. Alexander; note dated February 20, 1907.
  - Allen, Charles Dexter, 1899 1900; 12 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Includes two signed prints; some plates for Frances Louise Allen and Sylvia Marie Allen; two letters from C. D. Allen; and a newspaper clipping entitled, "The Token."
  - Allison, Charlotte D., undated; 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - American Institute of Electrical Engineering, Library of the, 1904; 15 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Andrews, William Loring, 1894 1896; 17 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Armour, George Allison, 1898 1910; 5 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Includes two signed prints; letter to Mrs. Merrill from G. Armour dated July 27, 1910.
  - Armstrong, Charles D., undated; 4 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Authors Club Library, 1897; 6 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Avery, Ellen Walters, 1893 1894; 6 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Baillie, William E. and Gertrude M., 1899 1907; 17 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Includes one signed print; letter from [William] Baillie to Madam dated August 26, 1907; letter dated August 16, 1899.
  - Bakewell, Allan C. and Alice G., 1893 1907; 12 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Includes one signed print; two trial proofs; letter from A. C. Bakewell to Mrs. M. E. Rath-Merrill dated April 8, 1907.
  - Baldwin, Sarah Rodman, 1901; 4 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Balken, Edward Duff, 1898 1907; 7 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Includes one signed print; letter from E. D. Balken to Mrs. M. E. Rath-Merrill dated March 4, 1907; letter from E. D. Balken to Mrs. Rath-Merrill dated January 19, 1898.
  - Bar of the City of New York, Association of the, 1895 1907; 18 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Barger, Samuel F., 1895; 4 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Barnes, John Sanford, 1901; 6 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bates, James Hale, 1894 1910; 6 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Includes letter from Mary Bates Spaulding to Mrs. Merrill; note with header "James Hale Bates;" paragraph behind one of the mounted plates.
  - Belasco, David, undated; 1 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Belknap, Helen Runyon, undated; 3 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Bernheim, A. C., 1895; 13 items (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Includes note labeled "A. C. Bernheim."
  - Bernheim, Henry C., 1894; 8 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Bernheim, Julius C. and Emily S., undated; 7 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Bierstadt, Edward Hale, 1894 1896; 13 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Includes four signed prints; note dated December 19, 1896.
  - Biltmoris (George W. Vanderbilt), 1895; 13 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Includes two newspaper articles describing death of GWV; letter to Mrs. Mary E. Roth-Merrill from GWV.
  - Bishop, Natala Washburne, 1902; 11 items (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Includes four signed prints.
  - Bixby, Emma Stuart and W. K., 1906; 11 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Includes letter from W. K. Bixby to Mrs. Ruth Merrill.
  - Black, Henry Van Deventer, 1906; 7 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Includes one print signed by French; two prints signed by H. Black; obituary for Henry V. Black; letter to Mrs. M. E. Rath-Merrill from HVD Black.
  - Blackwell, Henry, 1899 1915; 26 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    Includes three signed prints; typed article on bookplates; letter to Mrs. Rath-Merrill from H. Blackwell.
  - Bliss, Caroline Seagrave, 1903; 8 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Bliss, Catherine A., 1896; 3 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Boas, Emil Leopold, 1899; 4 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Borden, Matthew C. D., 1907; 7 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    Includes letter to Mrs. Mary E. Rath Miller from M.C.D. Borden dated January 30, 1907; typewritten note regarding plates; packet of excerpts from the August 11, 1912 Ohio State Journal.
    Related Archival Materials note
    The Borden design is a replica of the Sovereign design (Box 7, Folder 25), with a crown instead of an eagle.
  - Borland, Harriet Blair, undated; 3 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Bowdoin, W. G., undated; 2 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Bradshaw, Sidney Ernest, 1898; 6 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    Includes two signed prints
  - Brainerd, Agnes Mary, undated; 5 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Brainerd, Eveline Warner and Helen Elvira, 1893; 26 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Brainerd, Ira H. and Martha E., 1905 1907; 11 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    Includes one print signed by French; one print signed by F. A. Coombs; letter to Mrs. Rath-Merrill from Martha Brainerd dated July 29, 1907.
  - Brandegee, John H. (Fund), 1906; 1 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Brewer, William Augustus, 1903 1908; 16 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    Includes one signed print; typed note with handwriting by W. A. Brewer dated June 20, 1904; letter to Mr. Spenceley from W. A. Brewer dated May 17, 1907; letter to Mrs. Merrill from W. A. Brewer dated March 10, 1908.
  - Brown, Eleanor Bonney, 1911; 3 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    Includes one signed print by A. J. B[rown], Sc.
  - Brown, Georgette, undated; 5 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Brown, Grace Overton, undated; 1 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    Includes inscription from the engraver, A. J. Brown.
  - Buck, John H., 1910; 7 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    Includes letter to Mrs. Mary E. Rath-Merrill from John H. Buck dated May 20, 1910.
  - Bull, William Lanman, 1907; 4 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    Includes letter to Mrs. M. E. Rath-Merrill from Geo. F. Bauer, secretary, dated February 1, 1907.
  - Bullock, James Wilson, 1902; 10 items (Box 2, Folder 53)
    Includes one signed print; sheet giving detail on plates; letter to Mrs. Rath Merrill from James W. Bullock dated January 8, 1902.
  - Burke, Edward F., 1907; 7 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    Includes letter to Mary E. Rath-Merrill from Edward F. Burke dated February 25, 1907.
  - Burnham, William Henry and Katharine French, 1902-1907; 10 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    Includes two signed prints; letter to William G. Bowdoin from Katherine French Burnham dated June 7, 1903; typed page on the history of the name "Burnham."
  - Byrd, 1899; 6 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    E. D. French re-engraved the Jacobean bookplate of William Byrd of Virginia that was originally designed by Maverick. French's design was used by Francis Otway Byrd, George H. Byrd, Richard Evelyn Byrd, and William Byrd (of New York).
  - Candidati, 1897; 15 items (Box 2, Folder 57)
    Includes one signed print; note about the Candidati design by E. D. French.
    This ex-libris design was used by members of a society of women writers, including the following individuals: Eveline Warner Brainerd, Helen Hunt Daly, Georgiana Goddard King, Kate Dickinson Sweetser, and Sarah King Wiley.
  - Carnegie, Lucy Coleman, 1899 1905; 7 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    Includes front of an envelope addressed to Mrs. M. E. Rath-Merrill dated April 23, 1905.
  - Cary, Katharine Thomas, undated; 7 items (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Chaignon, de, 1901; 6 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    Includes one signed print; note from de Chaignon to E. D. French.
  - Chamberlain, Elisabeth, 1900; 4 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Champaign Public Library, 1895; 6 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Cheney, Alice S., 1900; 5 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Chew, Beverly, 1895 1896; 18 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Church, E. D., 1895; 6 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Cincinnati Law Library (Rufus King Fund), undated; 7 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    Includes one trial proof; portrait of Rufus King engraved by T. Kelly from original by Stuart and example of King's personal armorial bookplate.
  - Clark, Charles E., MD, 1894; 30 items (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Clark University, 1904; 10 items (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Clough, Micajah P., 1896; 10 items (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Colonial Dames of America, 1894; 4 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Connecticut Society of Colonial Wars, 1901 1928; 13 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    Includes six signed prints; note from 1928.
  - Connell, William, 1897; 7 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Cosmos Club, The, 1906; 9 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    Includes one signed print; photograph of the Cosmos Club.
  - Coutant, Richard B., 1894; 9 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    Includes two signed prints; one trial proof.
  - Cox, Jennings Stockton, 1898; 5 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Crerar Library, The John, 1894-1896; 21 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    Includes one trial proof.
  - Cushing, Harvey, 1898; 10 items (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Dana, Charles L., 1898; 9 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Davis, Cora Paschall, undated; 4 items (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Day, Elsie Lewis, 1897; 2 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Deats, Hiram Edwards, 1894 1907; 10 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    Includes letter to M. E. Fleming from H. E. Deats dated January 23, 1907.
  - De Vinne, Theo, 1895; 9 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Denver Club, The, 1896; 10 items (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Digamma Library, undated; 4 items (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Dill, James B., 1902; 6 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    Includes one signed print; one trial proof; original pen and ink sketch with photographic portrait of Dill.
  - Dimock, George Edward, 1904; 5 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Downes, Mary Lois Seagrave, 1905; 3 items (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Dows, Tracy, 1896; 6 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Drexel, Lucy Wharton, 1904; 8 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Duryee, George Van Wagenen and Margaret Van Nest, 1899; 5 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Eastbrook, John, 1915; 2 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Ellsworth, James William, 1895; 7 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Emmet, Thomas Addis (Collection of), 1896; 3 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Field Memorial Library, 1901; 3 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Fischer, Lucius G., 1905 1908; 5 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Foot, Margaret Horner, 1907; 6 (Box 3, Folder 96)
    Includes letter from Mrs. Rath Merrill to Mrs. Horner Foot Jr. requesting bookplates; response from M. H. F.
  - Foote, Charles B., 1894; 7 (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Francis, Christina D., 1906; 1 (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - French, Edwin Davis, 1893-1903; 52 (Box 3, Folder 99)
    Includes two signed prints; one trial proof; sketch; correspondence with Mrs. Rath-Merrill; photographs of French.
  - French, Edwin Davis (Miscellaneous), 1893-1906; 67 (Box 3, Folder 100)
    Includes signed photograph.
  - French, Mary Brainerd, 1893 1894; 13 (Box 4, Folder 101)
    Includes envelope to Mrs. M. E. Rath-Merrill.
  - Frick, Henry Clay, 1906; 9 (Box 4, Folder 102)
    Includes two trial proofs.
  - Furman, Dorothy, 1902; 9 (Box 4, Folder 103)
    Includes one signed print; partial letter.
  - Gage, Homer, 1902; 2 (Box 4, Folder 104)
    Includes correspondence with Mrs. Rath-Merrill.
  - Gage, Mabel Carleton, 1901; 2 (Box 4, Folder 105)
  - Gale, Edward Courtland, 1899; 6 (Box 4, Folder 106)
  - Godfrey, Jonathan, 1894; 9 (Box 4, Folder 107)
  - Goldsmith, Abraham and James A., 1898; 9 items (Box 4, Folder 108)
    Includes correspondence between Mary E. Rath-Merrill and Abraham Goldsmith.
  - Goodrich, J. King, undated; 6 items (Box 4, Folder 109)
  - Goodwin, Elizabeth Sage; Francis, James J.; and Philip Lippincott, 1894 1903; 20 (Box 4, Folder 110)
  - Gould, George J., 1906; 6 (Box 4, Folder 111)
    Includes letter to Mary. E Rath-Merrill; newspaper article.
  - Gray, Adelle Webber and Chipman, John, 1897; 10 (Box 4, Folder 112)
  - Greene, Francis Bunker, undated; 4 items (Box 4, Folder 113)
  - Grolier Club, 1894; 23 items (Box 4, Folder 114)
    Includes two signed prints; envelope from Mrs. M. E. Rath-Merrill.
  - Haber, Louis I., 1894; 4 (Box 4, Folder 115)
  - Harbor Hill, 1901; 5 (Box 4, Folder 116)
  - Harper, Henry H., 1904; 9 (Box 4, Folder 117)
    Includes one signed print; letter to Mrs. M. E. Rath-Merrill; first few pages of book by Harper.
  - Hartshorne, Mary Minturn, 1897; 6 (Box 4, Folder 118)
  - Harvard College Library, 1897 1906; 72 (Box 4, Folder 119)
    Includes 23 signed prints; correspondence with Mrs. Rath-Merrill; ephemera.
    Specific designs include: Cercle Francais, Child Memorial, Harvard Union, Hohenzollern Collection, Societatis Signeti.
  - Harvey, George, 1905; 5 (Box 4, Folder 120)
    Includes photograph of Mrs. George Harvey.
  - Havemeyer, William Frederick, 1895; 10 items (Box 4, Folder 121)
  - Heckscher, John Gerard, 1902; 15 items (Box 4, Folder 122)
  - Herter, Christian Archibald, 1896; 4 items (Box 4, Folder 123)
  - Hoe, Ruth Lancaster, 1903 1907; 6 (Box 4, Folder 124)
    Includes correspondence dated 1907.
  - Hoffman, Eugene Augustus and Samuel Verplanck, 1903 1904; 10 (Box 4, Folder 125)
    Includes one signed print; two newspaper clippings.
  - Holbrook, John S., 1905; 7 (Box 4, Folder 126)
  - Holden, Alice C., Edith, Edwin B., and Edwin R., 1894 1895; 28 (Box 5, Folder 127)
    Includes five signed prints; letter to Madam dated 1907.
  - Hooper, Nona Newlin, undated; 1 item (Box 5, Folder 128)
  - Hopkins, Robert Emmet, 1900; 5 (Box 5, Folder 129)
  - Horsford, Cornelia, 1899; 5 (Box 5, Folder 130)
  - Jackman, L. H. and S. E., 1906; 6 (Box 5, Folder 131)
  - James, Walter B., 1900; 4 (Box 5, Folder 132)
  - Jones, Timothy, 1893; 8 (Box 5, Folder 133)
  - Jordan, Elizabeth, 1906; 3 (Box 5, Folder 134)
  - Kahn, O. A., 1897; 7 (Box 5, Folder 135)
  - Kalbfleisch, Charles Conover, 1894; 6 items (Box 5, Folder 136)
  - Keyes, Helen, undated; 4 items (Box 5, Folder 137)
  - Kingsbury, Edith Davies, 1897; 5 (Box 5, Folder 138)
  - Lambert, Samuel W., 1898; 6 (Box 5, Folder 139)
  - Lamson, Edwin Ruthven, 1896; 5 (Box 5, Folder 140)
  - Larner, John B., 1900; 4 (Box 5, Folder 141)
  - Lawrence, Emily Hoe, 1894; 5 (Box 5, Folder 142)
  - Lee, Georgia Medora, 1904 1910; 17 (Box 5, Folder 143)
    Includes three signed prints; letter to Mrs. Merrill from Georgia M. [Pustin] dated June 29, 1910.
  - Leeds, Warner Mifflin; Louise Taylor Hartshorne.; and William Bateman, undated; 7 (Box 5, Folder 144)
  - Lefferts, Marshall Clifford And Mollie Cozine, 1894 1897; 17 (Box 5, Folder 145)
  - Leggett, Cora Artemisia, 1894; 6 (Box 5, Folder 146)
  - Lemperly, Paul, 1897; 16 items (Box 5, Folder 147)
    Includes five signed prints; postcard to Mrs. M. E. Rath-Merrill.
  - Little, Arthur West, 1900; 5 (Box 5, Folder 148)
  - Livermore, John R. and J. W., 1900 1906; 18 (Box 5, Folder 149)
  - Lombard, Herbert Edwin, 1908; 8 (Box 5, Folder 150)
    Includes two prints signed by A. J. Brown, Sc.
  - Long Island Historical Society, 1901; 13 items (Box 5, Folder 151)
    Includes five signed prints; one trial proof.
  - Loveland, John W. and Lee Partridge, 1900; 5 (Box 5, Folder 152)
  - Lovett, Benjamin Barnes, 1904; 7 (Box 5, Folder 153)
    Includes two signed prints; letter to Madam from [Benjamin] B. Lovett dated April 4, 1907.
  - Lowenstein, L. B., 1894; 6 (Box 5, Folder 154)
  - Lyman, Annie, 1903; 4 (Box 5, Folder 155)
  - Mackay, Katharine, 1899 1901; 5 (Box 5, Folder 156)
    Includes several newspaper articles with photos; plate for Harbor Hill.
  - Macy, Valentine Everit, 1896; 6 (Box 5, Folder 157)
  - Mansergh, Richard Scott, 1895; 12 items (Box 5, Folder 158)
  - Marshall, Frank Evans and Juliani, 1895 1897; 25 (Box 5, Folder 159)
    Includes five signed prints; three trial proofs; correspondence; photograph.
  - Massachusetts General Hospital, 1899; 6 items (Box 5, Folder 160)
  - McAlpin, Charles V., 1904; 4 (Box 5, Folder 161)
  - McCarter, Robert H., 1896; 5 (Box 5, Folder 162)
  - McKee, Thomas Jefferson, 1895; 9 (Box 5, Folder 163)
  - McLaughlin, Edward T. (Memorial), 1896 1897; 40 (Box 6, Folder 164)
    Includes 18 signed prints; one trial proof; correspondence between French and George Dudley Seymour; artist sketch; copper plate; small book.
  - Merriman, Roger Bigelow, 1901; 8 (Box 6, Folder 165)
  - Messenger, Maria Gerard and Elizabeth Chamberlain, 1895 1896; 36 (Box 6, Folder 166)
    Includes one signed print; one trial proof; inscription on verso of one plate; letter to Mrs. Rath-Merrill from Maria Gerard Messenger dated [April] 17, 1903.
  - Metcalf, Esther Pierce, 1906; 8 (Box 6, Folder 167)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1895; 37 items (Box 6, Folder 168)
    Includes five signed prints; three trial proofs.
  - Moore, Louise Taylor Hartshorne, 1899 1903; 7 (Box 6, Folder 169)
    Includes newspaper articles; letter to Mrs. Mary E. Rath-Merrill dated August 14, 1907.
  - Morgan, A. J., 1896; 10 items (Box 6, Folder 170)
  - Mynderse, Wilhelmus, 1903; 8 (Box 6, Folder 171)
  - New York Public Library, undated; 2 items (Box 6, Folder 172)
  - New York Society of Colonial Wars, undated; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 173)
  - New York Yacht Club, 1900; 16 items (Box 6, Folder 174)
  - Nimick, Florence Coleman, 1898; 6 (Box 6, Folder 175)
  - Notman, John, 1904; 4 (Box 6, Folder 176)
  - Odd Volumes, Club of, 1895; 15 items (Box 6, Folder 177)
    Includes five signed prints.
  - Ohio State University Library, 1915; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 178)
  - Osborn, Henry Fairfield, undated; 6 items (Box 6, Folder 179)
    Includes newspaper article.
  - Osborne, Thomas Mott and Agnes Devens, 1895; 9 (Box 6, Folder 180)
    Includes one trial proof; newspaper articles.
  - Overton, Marion Francis, undated; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 181)
    Includes letter from Miss Marion F. Overton dated February 25, 1911.
  - Oxford Club, 1894; 7 (Box 6, Folder 182)
    Includes two signed prints; note from French.
  - Palmer, Lowell Mason and Lowell Melvin, 1903 1904; 20 (Box 6, Folder 183)
    Includes one signed print; letter to Mrs. Mary E. Rath Merrill from Lowell M. Palmer.
  - Phillips, Amy Louise, undated; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 184)
  - Phillips, William, 1901; 8 (Box 6, Folder 185)
  - Players, The, 1894; 12 items (Box 6, Folder 186)
  - Plummer, Mary Emma, 1896; 10 items (Box 6, Folder 187)
    Includes two signed prints; ephemera.
  - Porter, Nathan T., Jr., 1900; 7 (Box 6, Folder 188)
  - Prescott, Eva Snow Smith, 1898 [1915]; 9 (Box 6, Folder 189)
    Includes two signed prints; letter to Mrs. M. E. Rath Merrill from Prescott dated [1915].
  - Preston, George M., undated; 6 items (Box 6, Folder 190)
  - Princeton University Library, 1897; 8 items (Box 6, Folder 191)
    Includes one signed print; letter to Madam from E. [L] Richardson dated May 18, 1905.
  - Pyne, M. Taylor, Percy Rivington, and R. Stockton, 1895-1907; 22 (Box 6, Folder 192)
    Includes one signed print; letter and envelope to Mrs. Mary E. Rath Merrill dated April 16, 1907.
  - Queen's University, 1905; 6 (Box 6, Folder 193)
  - Ranney, Henry C. and Helen B., 1897; 5 items (Box 6, Folder 194)
  - Reid, Whitelaw, 1894; 12 items (Box 7, Folder 195)
  - Richards Memorial Library, undated; 6 items (Box 7, Folder 196)
    Includes two trial proofs; original sketch.
  - Richards, Walter Davis, 1901; 6 (Box 7, Folder 197)
  - Robinson, C. L. F. and Mary Barber, 1900 1904; 18 (Box 7, Folder 198)
    Includes three signed prints; letter to Mrs. Mary Merrill from C. L. F. Robinson dated May 29, 1907.
  - Rogers, William Beverley, 1902; 11 items (Box 7, Folder 199)
  - Rowe, Henry Sherburne, 1894; 10 items (Box 7, Folder 200)
  - Rowland, Henry A. (Memorial Library), 1903; 7 (Box 7, Folder 201)
    Includes letter to Mrs. Mary E. Rath-Merrill dated March 4, 1907.
  - RJS, undated; 1 (Box 7, Folder 202)
  - Sabin, Ruth Mary, 1897; 9 (Box 7, Folder 203)
  - Salmon, Lucy Maynard, 1900; 6 (Box 7, Folder 204)
    Includes one signed print; letter to My Dear Friend dated May 14, 1910.
  - Sampson, Florence de Wolfe, 1898; 4 items (Box 7, Folder 205)
    Includes one signed print; letter to Mrs. E. [Pohe] Sampson dated March 2, 1911.
  - Sayler, John R., 1906; 4 (Box 7, Folder 206)
  - Scripps, James Edmund, 1896; 6 (Box 7, Folder 207)
  - Sedgwick, Henry Renwick, 1899; 4 (Box 7, Folder 208)
    Includes two letters to Mrs. Mary E. Rath-Merrill from H. R. Sedgwick.
  - Sedgwick, Robert, 1896; 21 items (Box 7, Folder 209)
  - Sheffield, Katherine Cecil Sanford (Gift of), 1898; 8 (Box 7, Folder 210)
  - Sherman, William Watts, 1901; 4 (Box 7, Folder 211)
    Includes letter to Mrs. Merrill, unsigned, dated January 31, 1907.
  - Sherwin, Henry A., 1896; 10 items (Box 7, Folder 212)
  - Sherwood, Samuel Smith, 1898; 6 (Box 7, Folder 213)
  - Simmons, Parke E., 1906; 7 (Box 7, Folder 214)
  - Simon, Herman, 1904; 12 items (Box 7, Folder 215)
  - Mark Skinner (Library), 1898 1905; 16 (Box 7, Folder 216)
    Includes one signed print; letter to Mrs. M. E. Rath-Merrill from Clara M. Chamberlain dated January 24, 1905.
  - Slade, Mabel, 1904 1907; 4 (Box 7, Folder 217)
    Includes letter to Mrs. Rath-Merrill from Mabel Slade dated January 31, 1907.
  - Smith, Henry A. and Mary Nixon, 1898 1905; 12 (Box 7, Folder 218)
  - Sovereign, 1896; 9 (Box 7, Folder 219)
    The Sovereign design is replicated in the Borden design (Box 2, Folder 5) with an eagle instead of a crown.
  - Sprague, Mary Bryant, 1904; 19 items (Box 7, Folder 220)
    Includes 15 signed prints.
  - Stearns, John Lloyd, 1897; 8 (Box 7, Folder 221)
  - Stevens, Harriette M., 1905; 11 items (Box 7, Folder 222)
  - Stickney, Edward Swan, 1898; 6 (Box 7, Folder 223)
  - Stratton, A. Dwight, 1898; 15 items (Box 7, Folder 224)
  - Sutton, Frederick Judson Holden, 1908; 5 items (Box 7, Folder 225)
  - Symon, Martha A., undated; 3 items (Box 7, Folder 226)
  - Taft, Theodore Eleanor, undated; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 227)
  - Talmage, John F., 1899; 6 (Box 7, Folder 228)
  - Tatlock, William and Helen Woodruff, 1893; 16 (Box 7, Folder 229)
    Includes one signed print; one trial proof.
  - Taylor, Charles H., Jr., 1896; 15 items (Box 8, Folder 230)
    Includes two signed prints; one color print.
  - Thorne, Katherine C. S., 1896; 13 items (Box 8, Folder 231)
  - Toedteberg, Emma, undated; 2 items (Box 8, Folder 232)
  - Townsend, James M., 1910; 4 (Box 8, Folder 233)
  - Truesdell, Winfred Porter, 1904; 9 (Box 8, Folder 234)
  - Twentieth Century Club, 1898; 7 (Box 8, Folder 235)